cbpp.org 2019-06-07

# Privacy Policy | Center on Budget and Policy Priorities

The Center on Budget and Policy Priorities (CBPP) is committed to protecting the privacy and security of your online information.  Some information is collected automatically when you visit us online to maintain the safety and security of our websites and to help improve their usability and contents.  You may choose to share other information with us when you try to interact with the site such as when you register for events, subscribe to email lists and make donations.   This policy describes how we collect and use your information online.    

If you have further questions about our privacy practices, please contact us at:

Email: [itdepartment@cbpp.org](mailto:itdepartment@cbpp.org)

US Mail:

Executive Vice President for Operations  
Center on Budget and Policy Priorities  
1275 First Street, NE  
Suite 1200  
Washington, DC 20002

#### **Information We Collect Automatically on Our Website**

Like most organizations, when you use our website CBPP collects non-personally identifiable data in an aggregated and anonymous form.  This data may include your IP, domain, URLs visited, and the date/time you visited them. We use this information to generate aggregate reports which summarize our website traffic, which we use to improve our site and its usability for our visitors. We do not attempt to track individual users and we do not link the web log information to any other database with the purpose of identifying individual website users.

#### **Personal Information**

CBPP does not collect personal information about website visitors without their consent. In cases when such information is requested to provide a service or respond to an inquiry, visitors only need to provide the minimal information necessary to interact with us. Typically personal information is collected to allow us to respond to inquiries and requests, or to allow you to comment on one of our blog posts, to register for events, to make online donations or to register for informational electronic mailing lists or data bases. 

It is our policy never to share, trade, sell or otherwise disclose personal information to third parties without a person’s informed consent except (a) where required by law (e.g. through subpoena, warrant or other legal process), or (b) to third party service providers that host services that we use in our interactions with you, such as event registration services, email distribution providers or online donation processing tool providers..  We work to ensure that these companies are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for any other purpose.

When requested, and where possible, CBPP will delete personal information from current operational systems.

#### **Website Tools**

We may make use of web beacons.  Pages of our website and the HTML-based emails and newsletters we send to you may contain small electronic files that permit us to count the users who have visited a particular page or opened an email and clicked through links.  Web beacons allow us to collect information about you when you open our emails, such as your IP address, your browser or email client and other details.  We use these tools to help improve our website and other materials.

#### **Links to Third-Party Sites**

CBPP’s website contains links to third-party sites.  We assume no responsibility for the information practices of websites a user is able to access through ours.  CBPP encourages all web visitors to review the privacy policies and statements of all externally-linked websites.

#### **Security**

CBPP has in place administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect the information that is under our control. We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving sensitive personal and financial data from our site. Please note, however, that security breaches can occur even if reasonable steps are taken to prevent such breaches; for example, we cannot guarantee that information provided through our sites will not be accessed without authorization on our servers or intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet. Please contact us if you believe there has been any breach of the security of our sites.

#### **Consent**

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and electronic communications, and not to any information collected offline.  By using our site, you consent to this privacy policy.  

#### **Details**

Details of the CBPP website privacy and cookie policies can be viewed using the links below.
